<resources>
    <!-- App general -->
    <string name="app_name">DidaktikApp</string>
    <string name="choose_language">Choose a language</string>
    <string name="language_eu">Basque</string>
    <string name="language_es">Spanish</string>
    <string name="language_en">English</string>
    <string name="menu_change_language">Change lenguage</string>
    <string name="menu_name">Settings</string>
    <string name="exit">Close dropdown</string>
    <string name="restart">Restart games</string>
    <!-- Botones -->
    <string name="intro_button">Start</string>
    <string name="intro_play_button">Start game</string>
    <!-- Introducción -->
    <string name="intro_title">Let´s discover Barakaldo, from rural to modern!</string>
    <string name="intro">Hi everyone! I´m Jolín, the most fun-loving character in Barakaldo! I´m
        so glad you´re here, because together we´re going to discover how this beautiful place
        has transformed from a rural village full of farmhouses into a modern, vibrant city. Along
        the way, we´ll visit some very special places, solve games and challenges, and learn
        amazing stories about our town.

        Get your curious eyes and your eagerness to learn ready! Each time you complete a
        challenge, you´ll unlock old and new photos of Barakaldo! At the end of the journey… a
        surprise and a diploma await you for becoming true Barakaldo explorers!

        Ready? Let´s go! Let´s discover Barakaldo, from rural to modern!</string>
    <!-- Juego 1 -->
    <string name="texto1_intro">Many years ago, Barakaldo was a town surrounded by fields,
        farmhouses, and mountains. Families helped each other, grew their own food, and went to
        the hermitage of Santa Águeda to celebrate festivals and ask for protection. The hermitage
        was a very important place for the townspeople, because they gathered there to sing, eat,
        and share moments together. Over time, Barakaldo changed, but the hermitage still reminds
        us how it all began.</string>
    <string name="pregunta1">What things do you think are still the same?</string>
    <string name="respuesta1_a">a) The hermitage is still standing</string>
    <string name="respuesta1_b">b) There are no more mountains</string>
    <string name="respuesta1_c">c) There are no parties</string>
    <!-- Juego 2 -->
    <string name="texto2_intro">The Church of San Vicente has been the heart of the village for
        many years. Here people gathered to pray, celebrate festivals, and meet with their
        neighbors. Look closely at the photo of the church and notice the elements that make
        it up: the Choir, the Altar, the Stations of the Cross, the Tabernacle, the Main Door,
        the Central Nave… Each one has its function and helps us understand what life was like
        in that time.</string>
    <!-- Juego 3 -->
    <string name="texto3_intro">In the Barakaldo market, people bought food and met their
        neighbors. Typical products were sold here: Barakaldo beans, talos (corn tortillas), cod
        in pil-pil sauce, and homemade sweets. The market was a place full of smells, colors, and
        sounds. Look at the clues in the word search and find the words that correspond to these
        foods.</string>
    <string name="pista3_1">A very typical legume from Barakaldo, it is eaten in stews</string>
    <string name="pista3_2">It is eaten at parties and is made from corn.</string>
    <string name="pista3_3">Fish cooked in pil-pil sauce</string>
    <string name="pista3_4">Typical sweet pastry from Barakaldo</string>
    <string name="respuesta3_1">BEANS</string>
    <string name="respuesta3_2">TALOS</string>
    <string name="respuesta3_3">COD</string>
    <string name="respuesta3_4">CAKE</string>
    <!-- Juego 4 -->
    <string name="texto4_intro">The Ilgner building was very important for Barakaldo. Here,
        electricity was produced for the factories and workshops. Thanks to the energy, the
        machines could operate, and the city grew considerably. Engineers, mechanics, and
        electricians worked here. The building still stands and reminds us how modern industry
        began.</string>
    <!-- Juego 5 -->
    <string name="texto5_intro">Many years ago, Barakaldo was a place full of factories and
        trains. Iron was extracted from the nearby mountains, and the loading docks were enormous
        structures used to load the ore onto ships. Trains brought the iron, and dockworkers moved
        it to the ships that carried it to other cities. Thanks to this work, Barakaldo became
        very important in industry.</string>
    <string name="mensaje5_1">This is where the trains carrying the iron arrived.</string>
    <string name="mensaje5_2">The iron was loaded onto ships that went to other countries.</string>
    <string name="mensaje5_3">The loading docks helped Barakaldo to grow a lot.</string>
    <!-- Juego 6 -->
    <string name="texto6_intro">In industrial Barakaldo, trains transported iron ore from the
        mines to the loading docks, where it was loaded onto ships. Thanks to the railway, many
        factories could operate continuously, and workers traveled daily on these trains.
        The railway was one of the driving forces behind Barakaldo´s growth.</string>
    <!-- Juego 7 -->
    <string name="texto7_intro">The Munoa Palace was the home of a very wealthy family. While many
        people worked in the factories, parties and dances were held here. It had gardens,
        paintings, and elegant furniture. Today, the Munoa Palace is a park open to everyone,
        where we can stroll and enjoy the history of Barakaldo.</string>
    <string name="titulo5_columna1">Workers</string>
    <string name="titulo5_columna2">Bourgeois</string>
    <!-- Juego final -->
    <string name="textofinal_intro">Barakaldo has changed a lot from its rural origins to the
        present day. We have old factories, churches, palaces, and parks that tell its story. All
        these places are part of our heritage, and we must take care of them so that future
        generations can also know them.</string>
    <string name="reflexionfinal">I would take care of ___ because...</string>
</resources>